https://www.tourettes-action.org.uk/92-privacy-policy.html

Contact the Helpdesk
In response to COVID-19 we have produced information and resources; and have made adaptations to our services.Download a list of consultants who specialise in diagnosing and treating TS.You can now download a list of behavioural therapists who deliver therapy to help manage tics, from our website.
Down to content
Main menu
HomeAbout TSWhat is TS?Symptoms Co-occurring symptomsCausesGetting diagnosedManaging TSBehavioural therapiesTelemedicineMedicationOther approachesNeurosurgeryResourcesFAQsFind supportHelpdeskOnline Support GroupsWorkshop eventsEducationEveryday lifeYoung peopleTA PassportTA ID cardsTA GrantsTS around the worldCommunityEventsTICfest TEENfestTICfest 4 AdultsEvents by RegionEvents CalendarYour TS videosTA onlineTA BlogTA NewsletterGet involvedMake a donationOther ways to donateLeave a legacyFundraise for TAFundraise your waySponsored challengesShopVolunteer for TAProfessionalsEmployersHealth ProfessionalsTeachersTraining and EventsBehavioural Therapy Clinical consultation sessionsNewsAbout TATA teamOur TrusteesTA accountsJobs at TAContact usMedia enquiriesPrivacy policyData Protection PolicyResearchResearch ProjectsCurrent projectsPrevious projectsSpotlight on researchersSupport with your researchAsk the expertsDonate
Down to contentSection menuAbout TATA teamOur TrusteesTA accountsJobs at TAContact usMedia enquiriesPrivacy policyData Protection Policy
Up to top
Privacy Policy & terms and conditions for website usageWelcome to the Tourettes Action website. If you continue to browse and use this website you are agreeing to comply with and be bound by the following terms and conditions of use, which together with our privacy policy govern Tourettes Actionâ€™s relationship with you in relation to this website.The term ‘Tourettes Action’ or ‘us’ or ‘we’ refers to the owner of the website whose registered office is Tourette Syndrome (UK) Association, The Meads Business Centre, 19 Kingsmead, Farnborough, Hampshire, GU14 7SR. Tourettes Action is a trading name of the Tourette Syndrome (UK) Association. Our company registration number is 2613993, registered in England and Wales. The term ‘you’ refers to the user or viewer of our website.
The use of this website is subject to the following terms of use
The content of the pages of this website is for your general information and use only. It is subject to change without notice.
Neither we nor any third parties provide any warranty or guarantee as to the accuracy, timeliness, performance, completeness or suitability of the information and materials found or offered on this website for any particular purpose.
You acknowledge that such information and materials may contain inaccuracies or errors and we expressly exclude liability for any such inaccuracies or errors to the fullest extent permitted by law.
Your use of any information or materials on this website is entirely at your own risk, for which we shall not be liable. It shall be your own responsibility to ensure that any products, services or information available through this website meet your specific requirements.
This website contains material which is owned by or licensed to us. This material includes, but is not limited to, the content, design, layout, look, appearance and graphics. Reproduction is prohibited other than in accordance with the copyright notice, which forms part of these terms and conditions.
All trademarks reproduced in this website, which are not the property of, or licensed to the operator, are acknowledged on the website.
Unauthorised use of this website may give rise to a claim for damages and/or be a criminal offence.
From time to time this website may also include links to other websites. These links are provided for your convenience to provide further information. They do not signify that we endorse the website(s). We have no responsibility for the content of the linked website(s).
You may not create a link to this website from another website or document without Tourettes Action’s prior written consent.
Your use of this website and any dispute arising out of such use of the website is subject to the laws of England, Scotland and Wales.
Copyright notice
This website and its content is copyright of Tourette Syndrome (UK) Association, trading as Tourettes Action - © Tourettes Action 2010. All rights reserved.
Any redistribution or reproduction of part or all of the contents in any form is prohibited other than the following:
you may print or download to a local hard disk extracts for your personal and non-commercial use only
you may copy the content to individual third parties for their personal use, but only if you acknowledge the website as the source of the material
you may not, except with our express written permission, distribute or commercially exploit the content. Nor may you transmit it or store it in any other website or other form of electronic retrieval system.
Disclaimer
The information contained in this website is for general information purposes only. The information is provided by Tourettes Action and while we endeavour to keep the information up to date and correct, we make no representations or warranties of any kind, express or implied, about the completeness, accuracy, reliability, suitability or availability with respect to the website or the information, products, services, or related graphics contained on the website for any purpose. Any reliance you place on such information is therefore strictly at your own risk.
In no event will we be liable for any loss or damage including without limitation, indirect or consequential loss or damage, or any loss or damage whatsoever arising from loss of data or profits arising out of, or in connection with, the use of this website.
Through this website you are able to link to other websites which are not under the control of Tourettes Action. We have no control over the nature, content and availability of those sites. The inclusion of any links does not necessarily imply a recommendation or endorse the views expressed within them.
Every effort is made to keep the website up and running smoothly. However, Tourettes Action takes no responsibility for, and will not be liable for, the website being temporarily unavailable due to technical issues beyond our control.
Privacy Policy
This privacy policy sets out how Tourettes Action uses and protects any information that you give Tourettes Action when you use this website.
Tourettes Action is committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this website, then you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement.
Tourettes Action may change this policy from time to time by updating this page. You should check this page from time to time to ensure that you are happy with any changes. This policy is effective from March 2018.
What we collect
We may collect the following information:
name and job title
contact information including email address, telephone number and postal address
demographic information such as postcode, preferences and interests
Medical information but limited to information about diagnosis related to Tourette Syndrome
We do not store credit card details nor do we share customer details with any 3rd parties.
Controlling your personal information
You may choose to restrict the collection or use of your personal information in the following ways:
whenever you are asked to fill in a form on the website, look for the box that you can click to opt in to receive information from Tourettes Action by email, sms, post etc.
if you have previously agreed to us using your personal information for direct marketing purposes, you may change your mind at any time by writing to or emailing us at admin@tourettes-action.org.uk.
We will not sell, distribute or lease your personal information to third parties unless we have your permission or are required by law to do so. We may use your personal information to send you promotional information about third parties which we think you may find interesting if you tell us that you wish this to happen. However, you can opt out of receiving this information using the online sign up forms.
You may request details of personal information which we hold about you under the Data Protection Act 1998. A small fee will be payable. If you would like a copy of the information held on you please write to Tourettes Action, The Meads Business Centre, 19 Kingsmead, Farnborough, Hampshire, GU14 7SR.
If you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete, please write to or email us as soon as possible, at the above address. We will promptly correct any information found to be incorrect.
Retaining and deleting personal data
This Section sets out our data retention policies and procedure, which are designed to help ensure that we comply with our legal obligations in relation to the retention and deletion of personal data.
Personal data that we process for any purpose shall not be kept for longer than is necessary for that purpose or those purposes.
We will retain your personal data as follows:
Personal data will be retained for a minimum period of 5 years following 01/01/2018, and for a maximum period of 25 years following 01/01/2018.
Notwithstanding the other provisions of this section, we may retain your personal data where such retention is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person.
Security
We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.
How we use cookies
A cookie is a small file which asks permission to be placed on your computer's hard drive. Once you agree, the file is added and the cookie helps analyse web traffic or lets you know when you visit a particular site. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences.
We use traffic log cookies to identify which pages are being used. This helps us analyse data about web page traffic and improve our website in order to tailor it to customer needs. We only use this information for statistical analysis purposes and then the data is removed from the system.
Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better website, by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us.
We also use cookies to remember the pages that you like to see on the website. This happens if you select to view information for a specific user group, the option to do so appears at the top of the website and is available for adults, young people, parents, doctors and teachers. We use a cookie to remember your selection so that the next time you visit the website you see all the information you want to.
Cookies used by our service providers
Our service providers use cookies and those cookies may be stored on your computer when you visit our website.We use Google Analytics to analyse the use of our website. Google Analytics gathers information about website use by means of cookies. The information gathered relating to our website is used to create reports about the use of our website. Google's privacy policy is available at: https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/.
You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. This may prevent you from taking full advantage of the website.
Links to other websites
Our website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.
Helpdesk
Calls and emails to the TA Helpdesk are treated with confidentiality, unless we feel that there is a risk to the caller or another individual, when we may break confidentiality.
Calls and emails to the Helpdesk are logged for reporting purposes which help us provide a better service. By providing us with your contact details you consent that we can store them on our secure database. The storage of this data conforms with the details in our privacy policy (above).
We use live chat software on our website (a messaging platform that enable live communication) , this is provided by Click4Assistance, a 3rd party UK based Software Company. Information regarding how the data is processed and stored can be viewed here.
If you do not wish for us to store your data you can contact us at any point in relation to the section above ‘controlling your personal information’.
Newsletter
By signing up to the TA newsletter you give us permission to email you with information and news relevant to TA and Tourette Syndrome. We will store your data securely within a third party system (mailchimp.com) and neither us or they will share it with any other parties without your permission.
If at any point you wish to be removed from our newsletter mailing list please contact us at help@tourettes-action.org.uk or click ‘unsubscribe’ on the bottom of the newsletter.
Online shop
Purchases from our online shop are logged on our secure database. We store your contact details and information about your purchase for our financial records. We do not store credit card details nor do we share customer details with any 3rd parties.
We aim to dispatch all orders from our shop within 7 working days of receiving your order. Orders are sent by Royal Mail, second class post, unless otherwise indicated.
Postage includes delivery in the UK. If you are outside the UK please contact us to discuss additional postage fees that may be applicable.
To request a refund or cancel an order, please contact us on 01252 362638 or email admin@tourettes-action.org.uk. We aim to respond and action all such calls and emails within 7 working days.
Social media
The TA website contains links to pages maintained by us on third party social media websites. The terms specified on those websites will apply to your use of those websites in addition to these Terms of Use.
You can contact us:
by post, to the postal address given below
using our website contact form
by telephone, on the contact number published on our website or 01252 362638.
by email, using the email address published on our website
Data protection officer
Our data protection officer's contact details are: Suzanne Dobson, CEO, The Meads Business Centre, 19 Kingsmead, Farnborough, Hants, GU14 7SR.
"Tourettes Action is a charity working to make life better for people with Tourette Syndrome"
About TATourettes Action works in England, Wales and Northern Ireland and is the leading support and research...TA accountsThe last three years of financial accounts from Tourettes Action can be viewed here.Latest newsMonday 27 July: The Neurological Alliance launch the results of their recent survey of more than 1,600 people with neurological...
Contact us
If you have any questions we would love to hear from you
Share
Site mapPrivacy policyData Protection Policy
© 2020 Tourettes Action. Reg Charity no: 1003317. Company registered in England and Wales number 2613993
Reg Office: Tourette Syndrome (UK) Association, The Meads Business Centre, 19 Kingsmead, Farnborough, Hampshire, GU14 7SR
Designed by Storm12
This website may use cookies to provide an improved experience. You can refuse these cookies by changing your browser settings.
To remove this message, click here to accept cookies.
